[Music]
a
w
[Music]
hello good evening good day everybody
Welcome to the latest episode of the ask
show I hope you're doing great all of
you and today I'm going to take some 15
or so questions from the comments and
the rest I will take from the live chat
that's what we will do today so it's
going to be a hybrid kind of session and
it's mainly history geopolitics all
right and current affairs as well so
before we get into the questions as
usual let us go and take a look at who
all is there on the live chat I can see
sual
agba yaj v n shria Kar niharika Gupta
Mar Panda netian vikrant mateti vianda
Lucario TBH Pand hello Tommy verti hello
AR chakti red johnv om Kiker hello
liberal mongelos pitra dhu Arun Prasad
Ramia anik Atul pritam random skull meul
Rajesh Babu will n Vladimir Abhijit
chav hello geopolitical dub chirak jeno
dato online
hello liberal okay vantom BoJack
Horseman vrv geopolitical dub red pamel
nandi hello long time Rahul pritam Kanan
ruzi metaz Zak Kiran lit Singh raat
Vishnu mohanan bavin
kakani aush Singh somit SpongeBob indan
Indian Hindu nationalist MC Lovin hello
bio
Sam
AK kushan
uh sonat anj Singh Sunil and everybody
else okay I'm gonna stop there I'm gonna
stop there uh before we uh get into the
actual uh questions let me remind you
all that I have this channel called
abijit chaa Clips on which I am putting
I'm going to be putting out and I'm
already in the process of doing it
putting up all the short clips of all
the answers I give in these live streams
let me and and it's on the pinned uh
chat message in the live chat so go
ahead subscribe if you want to see the
individual answers later on uh let me
just put that on the screen so that you
you you can see what I'm talking about
this is the channel abijit chaa clips
and I've got all these questions this is
from ask abijit
180 all the questions that have been
answered and before that ask abijit 179
as well and the process is on so all of
this all of the answers will come on
this channel I and I'll put a few few of
the answers on this channel as well but
most of them will be on the ask abijit
Clips Channel AB abijit CH Clips channel
so if you are interested in looking at
the individual answers then you can
subscribe to the Channel all right so uh
with that said let's take the questions
what questions do we
have mlen says the election results are
being shown on theaters in my city
Indian politics is wild yes election
results are
to be announced soon today is the 1st of
June and the election results will be
out of the 4th of June and today the
exit polls results are out which
obviously is not the final thing so yeah
Indian politics is indeed wild and uh
the big big days is almost Upon Us
fourth of June so yeah let's see how
that goes one can be
hopeful next question if it turns up
okay herel says the EU European Union
recently announced some financial aid
for manipur's recent hail storm but our
government denied it is that how the Far
East of India was converted as they
would give this Aid through the
NGS interesting interesting interesting
so what's going on the EU so there was a
hail storm and all that bad bad weather
in Manipur it caused a lot of damage in
the impal valley and the surrounding
regions a lot of crops were destroyed
lot of homes were destroyed and all that
very significant hail storm and the
European Union has very kindly decided
to send some money so let's uh let's go
and put that on the screen shall we uh
European
Union where can I find
this okay let's uh put that on the
screen
so so this is uh the news item the
European Union has made available over
22.6 million Indian rupees what is 22.6
million Indian rupees that's that's half
that's half a million Euros so it's
essentially peanuts okay first of all
they are offering pittance a pittance
peanuts half a million I'm not talking
about billion half a million euros okay
and this is in response to the recent
hail storm and heavy run that hit
Manipur in early May and here's the
statement by the EU let's put the
statement on the screen one second let's
put that
out um here is the actual news item from
the EU website itself European Union
provides this much money to assist
victims of severe weather in
India uh okay this humanitarian Aid will
provide crucial assistance to those most
affected in some of the ver areas the
aid will be now now this is important
pay attention to this the aid will be
delivered by EU humanitarian partner
ad it will prioritize whatever okay okay
so what the question is what is this ad
thing right what is
AD and let me explain what Adra
is so here's a tweet by Surya
Kar conversion racket operated by the
European Union the eu's humanitarian
partner ad is operated by the us-based
7th Day Adventist Church
why is the EU using a non-secular
conduit for dispersing so-called Aid
that a $4 trillion doll economy doesn't
need and that's a very pertinent
question so this ad is not even a
European
organization okay it's operated by
us-based 7th Day Adventist
missionaries so this is
clearly a vulture like
Behavior there is a humanitarian
disaster in a part of India people are
severely affected by bad weather so what
does the EU do it enlists the help of an
American conversion Factory to send
money to to route to to Route money into
Manipur okay so when there is a disaster
when there is a misfortune that has
befallen people they're going to try and
utilize that to convert people to
Christianity and as we know in the Far
East of India So-Cal Northeast uh
Manipur is the only hold out now I mean
Assam has been convert is being is being
converted to in a different direction in
a to a different religion nagaland
megala mizoram all of it is like almost
100% Christian now the the major power
in this region is the church okay and
the mes of Manipur are under threat now
I mean even among the Maas the last
Hindus left there um over two three lakh
have converted to Christianity so and
and they are under attacked by the by
the foreigners by the foreign
infiltrators into India the
cookies right they have been surrounded
and now the EU is using this opportunity
first of all they are under siege the M
Hindus and then there is the severe hail
storm so the the another Misfortune has
befallen them so let us utilize this
opportunity to convert as many of them
as possible it reminds me of what
happened in Nepal after the disastrous
earthquake that happened a few years ago
go and all these Christian organizations
were saying that okay many temples have
have been destroyed in Nepal by the
earthquake let's ensure that churches
are built in their place so these people
are like vultures absolute vultures when
something some some Misfortune befalls
unfortunate people they utilize that you
know to to convert them so what they
will do is they will come in and they'll
say okay here's a bag of rice you can
have it and your kids can have it but
you need to convert first or we're going
to give you various inducements and
incentives but you to convert for that
and so on so the EU is operating as a
conversion Factory and I'm sure I'm
pretty sure I'm not sure what the Indian
government has said but I'm pretty sure
the you Indian government has said we
don't need your godamn Aid keep it to
yourselves so you know this colonial
attitude still persists among the
Europeans and the EU the West the West
this Colonial attitude it's uh yeah so
I'm I'm glad you brought this up and
it's an important thing that we need to
take note of these activities by the EU
and by the West uh and this is a
geopolitical project conversion is a
geopolitical project the Chinese have
written about this in the past few
centuries the Japanese have written
about this and I think it's a reasonably
well-known phenomenon that once when
somebody in any Nation converts to an
abrahamic religion they typically uh
develop extra territorial
loyalties and the Japanese have written
about this that and and the Europeans
claimed that the Japanese persecuted
persecuted Christians Christian converts
there were reasons for this and the the
Chinese have written about this the term
rice Christian hasn't originated from
India I've shown this in a previous
episode the Chinese in the 19th century
wrote about rise Christians you know the
the Europeans would create the
disastrous problem in China people would
be starving and then they would offer
rice in exchange for conversions and
that's how so many Chinese became
Christians so the same tactics are still
in play in in a variety of different
ways so let's be aware of
this okay next question is by mlin and
the question is why is IND okay it's
three three people who asking the
question why is Indian gold reserves
stored in England 100 tons of gold is
being brought back by India isn't that a
great thing thing
happening and what's your take on the
RBI bringing back 100 tons of gold from
the bank of England to store it in India
so so India is one of the top 10 U
Nations worldwide in terms of gold
reserves and I'm talking about the gold
that is owned by the RBI The Reserve
Bank of India I think India is in the
ninth position or something the US is is
way ahead at the top okay in terms in
terms of gold reserves how many tons of
gold the the bank has the central bank
has in the case of the US it's a private
bank called the Federal Reserve it's
know not owned by the US government it's
not operated by the citizens of the
country it's a private bank and there it
stakeholders shareholders are unknown
that's the kind of country the US is
it's owned by a private trust
essentially or a private a bunch of
private private people anyway that's a
different story so the us is the largest
holder of gold in terms of the amount of
gold the Central Bank owns the RBI of
India is about I think probably number
eight or number nine and the amount of
gold we have is less than a thousand
tons RBI owned gold of course if you
factor in the other gold when it comes
to the amount of gold the people the
citizens possess and the amount of gold
in temples and all that's that's going
to be a tremendous amount of gold that
we have in India but the RBI is at
number nine in the global
rankings uh and about 5 450 or 500 tons
of this gold was in England the bank of
England in the city of London right and
this is an old tradition that we have
had that we give our gold for
safekeeping to the bank of England and
many other nations do this typically
generally these postc Colonial hardly
decolonized Nations and some other
nations as well and I've spoken about
this before that the real I mean when it
comes to the UK the UK is a third rate
poor country that is attached to the
city of London which is a First Rate
Global moneya laundering
Hub uh so we've had this gold sitting
there for I don't know how many decades
about 450 or 500 tons of gold so
recently we have brought back 100 tons
of gold back into India and it's going
to be stored in various locations safe
locations so these are our strategic
reserves why do we need to have these
reserves in a foreign country it just
doesn't make any sense to me makes no
sense logically or
strategically to have your strategic
reserves in somebody else's
possession okay I don't know do we get
some interest for it or whatever why do
we need that gold is the true is the
true store of value globally the US
dollar is a p is a bunch of paper that
is backed by by a bunch of thugs
military might that's all it is the US
dollar is not a reliable store of value
it's not a reliable store of currency
it's not a reliable
currency the only real value that you
can store is is in Gold so for example
we know the situation in the US people
are complaining about the the inflation
the rising price prices of petroleum and
how much a house costs these days okay
so in in 1980 a guy with a single
salary could buy a house and sustain his
whole whole family and today even if you
are working three jobs or whatever and
even your wife is working you still
can't afford to buy a house but here's
the
deal okay let's say you had a kilo of
gold in
1960 and let's say it can buy you a
certain kind of house of a certain size
on a certain amount of area property
that 1 kilo of gold today will buy you
the same house so the value of gold
hasn't changed but the value of the US
dollar has become garbage you understand
that's why gold is the only real store
of value it's extremely scarce it's hard
to it's hard to extract it's very scarce
very limited very rare and that's the
real store of value so when it comes to
Gold our strategic gold reserves we need
to have them in India and I'm glad the
the indan government has brought back
100 tons of gold let's bring the back
the rest of it back so yeah I don't know
why we have this gold Reserve stored in
England I think it's just a a colonial
tradition that the the the colonial
sahibs the great the great white Masters
are the true custodians of our things
and they will see they will keep things
safely for us that that that attitude
that that slavish attitude that mentally
coron attitude has persisted for so long
it's there among so many Indians even
today but I'm glad the government is
taking the right actions so good job
great job and yeah let's let's bring the
rest back whenever
feasible next question McLovin says what
are your views on the Slovak PM's
assassination attempt uh the guy's name
was Robert Foo if I'm not mistaken and
he's the Prime Minister President
whatever of Slovakia whatever they have
uh so a couple of weeks ago or so there
was an assassination attempt on him and
uh he was shot and he was in a critical
condition and uh I I hear that a day or
so ago maybe today maybe yesterday or a
couple of days ago he was released from
hospital which means that his life has
been saved he is no longer in danger and
he has been released from the hospital
which is a good thing now what are my
views on this so do we know where
Slovakia is or should we go to the map I
think we should go to the map we always
go to the map uh all right so where's
the
map here it is here is map so we go to
Europe right Eastern
Europe uh so here we have uh Europe and
you go to the Eastern side of Europe you
go north of Hungary and you have
Slovakia so this is the small nation of
Slovakia it used to be part of a larger
Nation called Czechoslovakia now you
have czechia in Slovakia Slovakia is the
eastern half of the the Earth while
Czechoslovakia now this gentleman the
Slovak uh leader Robert FICO so first of
all we have to understand okay we have
seen the map we know where it is we got
it okay let's take the map off the
screen now the point is this Slovakia is
a member of the European
Union Slovakia is also a member of NATO
so Slovakia is not a fully Sovereign
Nation when it comes to the EU there is
pooled sovereignty which means some part
of your National sovereignty goes out of
your nation's hands and it is it lies
elsewhere it lies in Brussels
essentially and Brussels is controlled
by Washington when it comes to Nato once
again you have pooled sovereignty so
once again you lose another part of your
sovereignty your military sovereignty
and strategic sovereignty foreign policy
autonomy all that stuff it goes out of
the window and that then lies in the
hands of NATO headquarters which is
again run by the Americans if you go go
higher and higher up it's the Americans
who actually call the shots so Slovakia
is a Nation that's part of both EU the
EU and
NATO and and we know what policies the
EU Nations have these days we see the
news all the time what happens in
Germany stabby stabby attacks what
happens in the UK the UK is not member
of EU it's a member of NATO so if you're
a member of NATO or EU you typically
have these these immigration policies
that are extremely welcoming of the
worst kind of
people typically mid military age men
single men who come without families who
generally come from certain
Nations you know Middle Eastern Nations
maybe Pakistan maybe
Afghanistan ex Fighters and so on or
African nations once again of of certain
religious inclinations and all that we
know what the situation is right now
this guy Robert Foo was very is
very strongly anti-immigration
and he believes in border security so he
has troops deployed on the borders with
Hungary and other nations to ensure that
no godamn immigrants enter the place his
enter enter his country he is against
immigration he has said he has said this
okay I'm don't it's not these are not my
words he said this that he that every
single Muslim person is under
observation in his country and he will
not allow the formation of Islamic
ghettos and all that okay how
islamophobic is that terrible terrible
condemnable obviously ly so when you
are the leader of a Nation that's a
member of the EU and also a member of
the of NATO and you don't follow these
dictat then obviously you open yourself
up to
certain
actions yes so I'm not surprised about
what happened to Robert FICO when your
minion does not tries to tries to betray
you you have to send the message you
have to send the message you got to send
the right message you got to set an
example this is this is the kind of
language you'll see in the movie The
Godfather right going to send a
message so that's how this works do you
remember Shinzo AB good man good man the
only good man I can think of when it
comes to Japan in the past several
decades what happened to Shinzo AB he
wanted changes in the constitution of
Japan he wanted the Japanese
self-defense forces to become genuinely
I mean a genuine Army a genuine military
force not not a glorified thing it's
still okay whatever so we know what
happened to shinzu a we know how and and
something similar has happened to Robert
FICO I don't know it what stage he'll
come back and resume his duties as the
prime minister or president prime
minister probably of
Slovakia right now the nation will be
governed by somebody else or somebody
else will be acting prime minister yes
so yeah it's it sent a very strong
message to
every political person in
Slovakia you behave or else you know
what can happen and so I'm not so I
don't know I mean I wonder who was
behind this I'm sure they've they've
apprehended some some random guy who
apparently was holding the gun and who
pulled the trigger but that's who who
was behind that that guy who who was
behind that similar to what happened
with AB they arrested some guy who was a
former Marine or something and they said
he had mental problems mental health
issues and no further investigation who
was behind that who was who was the
Puppet Master nothing similarly with the
in this case the Slovakian leader so
it's about look so Slovakia is this
small nation that is supposed to go
along with what they are told to do by
the big big daddy and when you don't do
that then you're going to face
consequences that is the harsh reality
of the world okay civilization is a thin
veneer like they say it's a very thin
veneer very thin facade and behind this
thin facade of civilization and
democracy and human rights you have the
rule of the Jungle that's geopolitics
that's how the real world Works Welcome
to the Real
World next question
okay let's put it
on okay give me a second there seems to
be ah here it is here we go okay music
31 339 says will the start of a war in
the Middle East change the world order
like it did in World War II in Europe
which means a complete transfer of
powers a new empires rising up okay
let's go to a map of the Middle East to
see the situation okay now we're looking
at Europe let's go towards uh West Asia
so this is the Middle
East we're talking about the the Arabian
Peninsula which is Saudi Arabia Yemen
Oman and the UAE and you also have
Mesopotamia which is Iraq and
Kuwait and then you have uh Syria and
the Eastern Mediterranean which includes
Israel Lebanon Jordan
and the the U then you also have uh
Egypt which you could say is kind of
part of the Middle East and you could
even bring turkey in and some people
would even include Iran in this matter
in this geographical region some people
would say Iran is part of kind of an
extension of uh the Indian subcontinent
whatever you want to say doesn't matter
it's up to you you decide how you would
like to look at the world now the point
is this the Middle East has always been
uh in crisis always some problem or the
other you had the Iran Iraq war which
was a proxy war between the US and Iran
which happened in the 1980s and it was a
disaster for both Nations then Iran has
been under sanctions tremendous
sanctions for decades and it has caused
Untold misery humanitarian disasters and
crisis in the nation and right now we
have the situation in the VAV Israel and
the Hamas that's going on and yes right
now there's action in Rafa right all
eyes on Rafa Alle apparently when it
comes to the useless Indian influencers
so-called Indian influencers so there is
this situation this war let's say going
on you know low intensity lowlevel war
between isra and the Hamas and Hamas is
based out of the Gaza
Strip uh so that's what's going on now
obviously as we know I've covered this
in the past that you had these problems
between Iran and uh Israel so an Irani
few the Iranian Consulate in Damascus
was bombed by the Israelis and the
Iranians they they hit Israel with a
large number of drones and missiles then
the Israelis hit back and you know
there's been these
tensions and uh there's a proxy war
situation going on obviously the
Iranians are a geopolitically active and
ambitious Nation they have proxies in
Iraq they have Proxes in Syria they have
proxies in Hamas they have proxies in
Oman I'm sorry not in Oman in Yemen the
hutis and much more in Iran could be by
now a nuclear capable Nation they may
have sufficient uh file material to to
build a few nuclear warheads and as we
know Israel is an Undeclared nuclear
power they have I mean apparently the
the number that's that's bandied around
is 90 nuclear warheads what type of
Warhead we're not sure maybe tactical
Warheads which is a lower yield thing
maybe
50 to 100 kilotons is kind of tactical
Warhead maybe bigger we don't know we
don't know it's all speculation so
that's the situation now here is the
deal none of these nations in the Middle
East
is either a great power or a superpower
there's only one superpower right now
the US and in the Middle East you don't
have a single great power you don't have
a single uh even a middle power Iran
could perhaps be a middle power you
could perhaps call Israel middle power
but that's about it and the balance of
power is such that none of these nations
are especially hold especially too much
of a large Edge over each other so you
have tensions between Iran and Saudi
Arabia Saudi Arabia wants peace in the
region UAE wants peace they don't want
tensions but this is going
on but none of these nations is capable
of destroying the world there are let's
say two nuclear Powers here okay Israel
and May maybe Iran is also nuclear power
but they don't have the capability to
destroy the whole world and none of the
really great powers are involved here
actually so in Syria you have Syria you
can say is is an ally of of Russia the
Syrian government exists and still stays
in is still in power only thanks to the
intervention of Vladimir Putin because
the Americans were trying to affect a
regime change in Syria and they had
almost succeeded with the help of
alqaeda and Isis and whatnot the
Americans believe me yes
uh so you have that then Iran is uh you
can say allied with Russia as well as
China and Saudi Arabia and Iran are
members of brick so there's a
complicated situation here but none of
the great powers are involved directly
in this region the Americans have some
troops in Iraq they have some troops in
the eastern part of Syria
allegedly and they have military bases
in Saudi Arabia and various other parts
of the region but uh not any direct real
involvement militarily so when it comes
to changing the world order and complete
transfers of powers and new empires
rising up that is something when which
happens when the greatest powers in the
world Collide so essentially we're
talking about a war between the US and
Russia that's what we're talking about
that's when some something like that
that sort of situation could arise I'm
not even considering China to be that
powerful of a Nation militarily the two
real great Powers one is a superpower
one is a near superpower of the US and
Russia Russia is way more powerful than
China militarily they can squash China
tomorrow if they want to but they they
want do that for a variety of reasons so
to after you understand all this you'll
realize that a war in the Middle East
will not change the world drastically of
course it will be a disaster for the for
the global economy because much of the
energy that the world needs the
petroleum energy it comes from the
Middle East so if there's a war there
and there's a blockade and all that then
that will be bad for the global economy
including the Indian economy and
whatever else so it can certainly uh
make a lot of difference in the world
very negative difference but it won't
change the
global order of power that's that won't
happen the war that is capable of doing
that is the is the Ukraine war and even
the Taiwan situation could be a game
changer so these are the two dangerous
Flash points India China is not that
much of a dangerous flash point in terms
of the world order of course two
gigantic Powers fighting is not good
thing but it won't change the world
order as such unless China is W wiped
out by India which is right now
unlikely all right next question okay a
bunch of questions together iwan Singh
says we hearing that NATO troops are
already on Ukrainian territory your
thoughts ROV says what are your thoughts
on Emmanuel macon's position on sending
NATO troops to Ukraine if required isn't
it an unnecessary provocation and what
will be the implications and Ean says we
hear that Ukraine will receive f-16s in
some time how will it change the war
what will happen if Ukraine does missile
strikes on Russian territory first of
all the ukrainians have been doing
missile strikes drone strikes Etc on
Russian territory I remember a few
months ago they had attacked a Russian
Air Base Airfield with drones and and
destroyed at least one uh large
transport Transport
Aircraft and they have been targeting
Russian facilities Etc with missiles
with drones the ukrainians have been
doing it for quite some time but the
real question is about
NATO so NATO troops have been on
Ukrainian territory for quite a while
perhaps since the beginning of the war
but they have been there in a specific
set of of of
uh in a specific uh role
okay so the role they've been playing as
far as we know is that of military
intelligence so they're providing
intelligence they're providing training
and that sort of things so they're not
involved in combat
operations okay unless you have
mercenaries so we know that American
mercenaries French mercenaries British
mercenaries have
been have have gone to Ukraine many of
them have also been killed but they are
not those those mercenaries were not
fighting for NATO they were US citizens
and UK citizens and whatever else
citizens but the the flag they were
carrying what was not the NATO flag I
think they were fighting as mercenaries
for
Ukraine and I I remember in 22 many of
those guys were you know found dead and
all that they were taken out in missile
strikes and whatnot so that is a
separate matter but NATO troops have
been on Ukrainian territory for quite
some time in these in in these roles
now
uh a couple of days ago one hears that
Joe Biden has said that has given the
green light to
Ukraine for
using NATO weapons against
Russia so right now it was until now it
was just arms it was just ammunition
mostly and lots of Aid billions of
dollars and all that but now NATO
weapons I'm I wonder which specific NATO
weapons will be will be used now but
yeah NATO Weaponry will be used against
Russia now they have given the green
light even the Germans have apparently
given the green light Germany is no
caller of shots in NATO Germany is a
vasal of the US and the US military
occupation but so it's the US that has
given uh Ukraine the green light for
doing this so you are seeing that we are
step by step inching towards further and
further
escalation it's called creeping normaly
you know they take an inch at a time
inch at a time and you you keep prodding
forward so the so from the from the side
of NATO from the perspective of NATO
they are inching forward and they're
going up they're ratcheting up the
escalation ladder and this is very
dangerous territory we are
in and once again you have spoken about
the F16 so in a few months maybe you
will get F16 16s in in Ukraine so the
ukrainians could use could be using soon
f-16s to Target Russian installations
and perhaps launch attacks on Russian
territory well once again that is
escalation and the Russians have been
cautioning NATO about this they are
talking
about what are they talking about
they're talking about World War II which
means when when you talk about World War
I It generally means nuclear war and
nuclear war is something you don't need
and now if you look at the two uh if you
look at the Russian nuclear stockpile
Visa with the American nuclear stockpile
the Russian stockpile is larger and they
have a significant amount of tactical
Warheads so tactical Warheads are lower
yield Warheads compared to strateg
strategic
warheads and tactical Warheads are what
you would call Battlefield nuclear
warheads Battlefield nukes so reasonably
small yield it will be localized
explosion it can take out large
concentrations of troops and tanks and
military installations so when you use
Battlefield nukes okay we hope it never
happens but if you use them you don't
need to be extremely precise and hit the
target right on on the dot you can just
you know explode the nuke in the general
vicinity of the Target and it's it's
going to ensure everything is out so
that's Battlefield nukes and the
Russians have said that they will use
nuclear weapons it's the doctrine
nuclear doctrine that if Russian
territory is under threat then nuclear
weapons can be used so we are in
dangerous territory now the Americans
are slowly inch by inch ratcheting up
going up the escalation ladder the
nuclear escalation ladder that's that's
very dangerous and when it comes to F-16
so if if the the ukrainians start using
f-16s it'll be a boost to the fire power
but it's not like the Russians will just
sit idle they have got a tremendously
powerful Air Force that which they have
not used at all and they what the
Russians are doing is very smart they
are keeping their real Firepower their
real assets in
reserve for for the eventuality that
they may actually have to fight nato in
the future right now it's just Ukraine
you can just at trite Ukraine fight a
war of attrition long War of Attrition
which is working just fine and it's it's
devastated the Ukrainian Armed Forces
but the real danger is not Ukraine from
Russia's perspective it is NATO the
combined might of NATO and that is the
real danger and that's why Russia has
not used any of its real major assets
like the Air Force and all that they
have not pressed their hundreds of
fighter planes into service none of that
has happened they are keeping everything
in reserve for that eventuality and of
course then they have the last option
which is the nuclear option which nobody
well I I keep saying that nobody wants
we don't want that so if Ukraine uses
f-16s then they they're going to well
it's going to cause a reaction action
reaction right yeah so dangerous times
and NATO I guess is just trying to see
how far they can keep pushing the
Russians keep pushing them keep pushing
them push them into corner and then who
knows what what will happen so not not
good this is not good at
all okay next
question is by Akash
Buller why and how did India recover
from colonialism much better than
African colonies like Somalia Chad and
Sudan does India's political structure
and Constitution particularly its
democracy have any influence on this
Divergent trajectory suggesting that
democracy has proven beneficial for
India okay so when it comes to African
nations Africa as we know was fully
colonized by the European powers Africa
was divided up by the Europeans in the
late 19th century and then the Germans
the belgians the the British the
Italians and whoever else is left they
all colonized various the Dutch uh and
so on the colonized various parts of
Africa they divided the whole place up
and they took various parts of it and
extracted everything of value out of it
total total complete destruction of
whatever was there and complete
extraction and even today in the 21st
century Africa is colonized in a variety
of ways so what the Europeans did was
they destroyed the the
traditional uh governance structures in
these kingdoms and Empires that they
conquered because they had Superior
technology so it was easy for them to
conquer these kingdoms and Empires when
you have guns and the other side of
Spears it's very hard for the spear guys
to to win against you I mean the Zulus
can try Shaka Zulu but yeah it doesn't
work in the long run so that's what they
did and they destroyed the the ruling
dynasties lineages all that they
destroyed the governance structure they
brought in for their foreign religion
and converted most of Africa is
converted to one of two abrahamic
religions nothing
almost nothing indigenous is left and
they ensured that whatever continuity
you had of governance was destroyed so
the entire governance structures and
mechanisms were wiped out of existence
so the only thing that was left was the
colonial governance structures and
mechanisms and when they let's say
allegedly decolonized Africa in the
1960s Etc this is there's this movie I
can recommend Ado Africa no Africa Ado
it's a not an easy one watch yeah but it
it kind of depicts the time period of
turmoil when the Europeans were
allegedly exiting Africa and giving
Independence to various African
nations but the kind of Independence
they gave was no different from
colonization so they would install a
puppet
government and they would rule by
proxy and uh they prefer dictators so
you pay the dictator some money and you
give them certain privileges they can
come and have a bank account in London
or wherever and you can treat them like
royalty and in return they will allow
you to keep
on pilfering the resources of their
country so that's how neoc colonization
works and it's still still going on that
way in Africa Africa is still colonized
through proxy so that is what happened
in Africa now the question is has India
recovered from colonization from
colonialism I'm lots of people very
smart very intelligent people people
they point they like to point out that I
speak in English so the reason I speak
in English is okay I'll not go into the
reasons because it's beside the point
the point is we all speak to each other
in English that tells us How Deeply
colonized we still
are if you don't speak good English
today you will not get a good job in
India if you don't speak English today
you will not know what the court
judgments are if you are unfortunate
enough to be in a court
case and there's so much more the entire
government Machinery of India is the
colonial governance Machinery I mean the
question I would like to ask is what do
collectors collect today you have a
district collector in every District
right what do they collect the entire
every single institution is a colonial
institution the education system is
further alienating Indians from their
own culture India is the only country
probably that doesn't teach its children
their own culture in the education
system so I don't agree that India is a
is a post colal Nation or a decolonized
nation or a nation that has recovered
from
colonialism I think we are taking the
first steps now towards recovering from
colonization
colonialism uh of course we have not
been devastated the way these countries
Somalia Chad Etc have been devastated
they have been devastated far worse than
us of course if you go back to 1947 the
average life expectancy of an Indian
person was 31 years that is kind of
Somalia Chad level okay so that's where
we were but we recovered from that
reasonably fast because of the
resilience of the Indian people the
large population the tremendous reserves
resources the nation has despite the
socialism that was imposed on India for
decades which kept India laboring under
the what the what some people like to
call the Hindu rate of growth which was
actually the nvan rate of growth and
once you once once you freed India from
that India just took off right India is
taking off off right now India is
growing at what 8.2% per year right now
last quarter I believe for last quarter
of the Year 2023 so the moment you
unleash you unshackle the country it
takes off so I think India's is
beginning to recover from colonialism
only now and even now there are so many
there are these millions masses of
mentally colonized Indians who have this
deep inferiority complex and
self-loathing so it so India's
trajectory has been different from the
that of the African nations
but I don't think it has anything to do
with the Indian
democracy in India's Constitution
India's Constitution is a colonial
Constitution by the way what is Indian
about the Indian
constitution there is nothing Indian
there is nothing btia about the Indian
constitution not a single word is
bhattia where are the Indian values
where is the where's all that nothing
it's all copy pasted from European
constitutions Western constitutions so
there is nothing about the Indian
constitution or the Indian democracy
that has contributed to India taking a
different path from the African nations
India's political structure is the
Westminster system which is Gastly it's
not right for India that political
system okay the Westminster system it
evolved over a thousand years on a small
island in the Atlantic
Ocean and that is completely unsuitable
for a subcontinent sized civilization
such as India India has to go back
eventually to its own traditional govern
system okay and we obviously are the
First Nation to have been a democracy
first civilization to have been a
democracy long before long before Greece
was even
born okay but ours was a different
system ours was a hybrid system so uh I
would not agree that democ this this
particular form of democracy has proven
beneficial for India or India's
Constitution which has been which has
never been ratified by the people of
India has done anything good for India
and the Indian political structure all
that it has nothing to do with all these
things India has taken a different
trajectory because of the resilience of
its people and and and and the great
energy the nation has despite everything
that has been imposed upon it the
Decades of nean socialism despite that
India has taken a different trajectory
so it has nothing to do with
the the Constitution or the democ the
the form of democracy that has been
imposed on India or any such thing it's
because of the resilience of India
itself that we have taken a different
path and hopefully we take a very
different path going
forward right next
question okay this is by Akash Buller
again why is nationalism shown as an
evil ideology in the west is it a
psychological after effect of the second
World War or are there deeper factors
behind beneath the surface
so is good question yes uh so look at
the
map okay let's look at the map what do
we see we see political lines on the map
right in Africa you have straight lines
everywhere drawn by Outsiders in India
we have these lines in Asia we have
various boundaries so every today we're
living in the west westfalian system the
nation state system so it's it's a
system in which every nation is supposed
to be Sovereign of course it doesn't
really work like that but we have
Nations and Nations
exist and every nation has the right to
exist independently from others and it
has the right to its own
self-determination sovereignty and and
of having of of having no interference
in its Internal Affairs and obviously
every population when it comes to these
nations every every national population
has the right to be proud of the nation
which is called
nationalism all right so nations are a
fact of life nations are a fact Nations
exist so why is it wrong to love your
nation and to be proud of your nation
why is it a problem why is why is it why
is it a big Taboo in the West
and to understand that we have to
understand the true nature of the
West let me give you an
analogy go back 2,000
years what did the West look like 2,000
years ago in the year 24 ad what was the
West like it was mainly rooted by the
Roman Empire right 2,000 years ago the
West was ruled by the Roman Empire
so once again
map so all the way from hispania which
is Spain today Spain to the British
Isles to the gulic Celtic regions which
is France Austria czechia Italy Etc not
Italy all that France Switzerland
czechia and so on to Germania which is
today's Germany to Eastern Europe th all
that and all the way to Anatolia which
is right now turkey and Juda and all
that all of this was under Rome even
North
Africa okay so all of
these regions were under were ruled by
Rome you can say that these nations
these various Nations that existed at
the time like Judea Germania and so on
and so forth
th and so on were ruled by Rome
including
Egypt
now do you imagine that in the year 24
ad the Romans
would have tolerated Any Nation having
nationalistic
sentiments do you think Rome would have
tolerated or encouraged nationalistic
sentiments in any of these nations that
it
ruled no that would be a threat to its
hegemony so they would crush any
nationalistic sentiment with an iron
fist as we know very well in case you
have read Roman history they did that
over and over and over again
right remember what happened in Judea
what they did to the to the Temple of
Solomon only one wall stands today who
broke the Temple of
Solomon the Romans why did they do
that yes so the Romans did not tolerate
any display or any nationalistic
sentiment in any of their
subject
Nations now today today you have the
West fan system sovereign every nation
is Sovereign or is it in the EU you have
pulled sovereignty so every nation isn't
really Sovereign it is Brussels that
decides the immigration policies
economic policies and all that affect
the the ordinary man woman child on the
streets in various nations in the EU so
where's the sovereignty it's pooled
sovereignty when you're a member of NATO
it's pooled
sovereignty pulled pulled all these
nations come together and become part of
NATO and they pull some of their
sovereignty together which means they
give up some of the sovereignty and who
gets the sovereignty NATO but who owns
the NATO United States of America who
owns the EU United States of America
whether you realize it or not whether
you want to admit it or not the United
States of America owns the EU and it
owns
NATO okay so the the US it is a
superpower but it's actually an Empire
that rules the world in such a way that
you don't realize it rules the world you
know what they say in business if you
are a monopoly it makes a lot of sense
to make people believe that you're not a
monopoly okay so when you had Microsoft
that was a monopoly in the 1990s and
2000s and so on it may it it made every
effort possible to convince the people
in the world in the government and the
courts that it was not a monopoly no no
no we are not a monopolistic Corporation
no Google also tries now why has it why
has Google renamed itself to
alphabet an alphabet is is a holding
company with all these different things
under it but the real deal is the search
engine and everything that comes with
that AdWords AdSense and whatnot so
Google also is trying its best to
convince the world that it's not a
monopoly it will try its best it will
try and obfuscate the truth Microsoft
did that as well
similarly the United States has done a
tremendously good job in making people
believe that they believe in human
rights and democracy and freedom and all
that when they're actually an
Empire so when you're an Empire and you
rule half the world or more you will not
tolerate any
nationalism okay and this has been this
has been the situation since 1944
1945 all right and that is why
nationalism is considered to be an evil
ideology in the West
you can say it's an after effect of the
second world war but the real effect is
that the US became the the global Empire
it took the took on the mantle from the
UK the British Empire the The Entity
continued but the the the center of
power was transferred from London UK to
Washington DC in the US and that's what
happened and since then they had this
Atlantic Charter in which they said oh
there wonderful things we believe in
democracy we believe in non interference
we believe in not changing borders we
believe believe in human rights and all
but if you look at their actual actions
it's the opposite of that so that's the
reason why nationalism is regarded as an
evil ideology in the west especially in
in Western Europe and all that in
Eastern Europe and Russia nationalism is
great in India well in India India is
conflicted because of the mental
colonization of most
Indians but yes there's been there's
been seeds of nationalism even in
Nations like Japan which have been
stamped out but yeah so that there you
have it that's the
answer Guardian 08 says I've been
watching a TV show called Shogun and
it's very interesting to watch Ancient
Japanese culture what happened to their
culture Japanese culture it is still
there but now Japan seems more viewed
for their cartoons and Anime which is
almost everywhere in Japan my question
is what happened to the Japanese they
used to be so ruthless especially in the
Second World War now they seem very
timid and weak with this anime and
cartoons being what they are known for
now we have to live in reality and war
is a real thing I personally don't think
that if Japan was ever in a war they
would win without us help what happened
to Japan is the question Japan used to
be this powerful Nation this great
Empire the Land of the Rising Sun it was
known for its uh the samurai period the
samurai you know and then you you had
the the Magi era the Mii period the Mii
restoration and that was the end of the
Samurai era and the beginning of the
Japanese
empire the Japanese Colonial Empire in
which they tried to pretend like they
were they were white people and they
behav in the same way as the westerners
aning territories and colonizing
colonizing countries and all that that's
what happened so here's what happened to
Japan Japan used to be a very
traditional Nation they were a closed
off nation and they knew how the West
behaves it's a colon It's a
rapacious colonizing Force they will try
and convert your people to their foreign
religion and use that that religion to
to to Fan extr territorial loyalties
among the among your population they
will try and exploit your nation's
resources and destroy your economy the
Japanese knew the West would do that
that's why they were a closed off
nation and you had the samura period
several centuries of that they had
Shogun in various Shoguns and all that
and the samura were staunch Buddhists
see the original Japanese religion
culture it's a polytheistic religion
called
Shinto so that is the original thing and
it is way closer to Hinduism than
Buddhism actually Buddhism is like a
voke form of Hinduism I think Alan wats
said that Buddhism is Hinduism stripped
for export anyhow so Shinto is there and
then you have Indian influence coming
into Japan in the third fourth Century
ad and Buddhism comes in and then Shinto
and Buddhism synchronize
syncretized together and Japan evolves
the syncretic culture over 1,500 years
and then you have the samurai who are
staunch Buddhists and they have this
code of honor this code of Life called
Bushido uh very it is very much like the
rajput code of honor essentially the
samuray code of honor very much similar
to that very disciplined life and all
all that and then you have in the 19th
century the destruction of the Samurai
system by uh a bunch of
uh bunch of plotters who were actually
in control of the mai Emperor's
government the Mii Emperor had become
just a puppet essentially and these guys
what they did was they destroyed the the
system of the Samurai they killed off
all the Samurai with using foreign
weapons so this is when Japan had opened
up and they had realized that if we
don't adapt to the to the ways of the
west then the then we will become
victims of the West so Japan destroys
the samurai system eradicates it
completely and suddenly becomes
completely in a decade or two completely
westernized they start wearing Western
dresses and start using Western weapons
and Western Battle Tactics and
strategies and they start conquering
other countries and uh and colonizing
other countries and the Europeans and
westerners are very impressed by the
Japanese ah look at these people just a
civilized ASAS yes so by becoming brutal
barbarians by and another thing the Magi
restoration did or attempted to do they
tried to portray Buddhism as a foreign
religion and they tried to eradicate
Buddhism from Japan did not work but
they succeeded in at least one thing
today the Japanese people regard
Buddhism as a foreign religion it's
still a Japanese religion but it's it's
it's a foreign origin before the miji
restoration Buddhism and Shinto were syn
syncretized together same Temple both
things today it's different so today
most Japanese they will do weddings and
all through the Shinto thing and when
they do their funeral it will be
Buddhist funeral that's that's the kind
of thing you have in Japan today uh so
that's what happened so Japan became an
a Nitro version of the West they started
conquering everybody and conquering
every all territories they fought the
Russians and defeated the Russians in
1905 they conquered manua and so much
more okay so I'll not go into all that
so they became
like uh a mega version of the west west
on steroids and then you have the second
world war in which they allied with
Germany and the Americans tested to
nuclear weapons on Japanese territory
Hiroshima and Nagasaki and Japan
eventually had to surrender and the the
emperor of Japan had to declare his
Humanity so the the emperor of Japan was
traditionally seen as a Son of God the
son of the Gods but after the surrender
to the Americans he had to declare his
humanity and renounce his Divine status
and such is the situation today as well
so that's what happened the Japan was
emasculated the they were they were
forced to swallow a new constitution
written in 1945 by the Americans even
today the same Constitution is in force
not a single word has been changed
changed and there are more than 130
permanent US military bases on Japanese
territory which means Japan is under
permanent US military occupation with a
foreign Constitution and their armed
forces are called the Japanese
self-defense forces so that nation has
been completely emasculated it has been
turned into Disneyland for the Americans
when the Americans want to go on
vacation they go to Japan and turn treat
the nation as Disneyland as Disneyland
so that is the situation in Japan so the
Japanese are just trying to cope the
best you know survive the best way they
can their economy has been destroyed
since the 1980s the plaza Accords BS the
trigger the Turning Point Japan's
economy is has been under in recession
for quite some time Japan is in in
danger of becoming a middle income
Nation from a high in nation and the
birth rates have fallen horribly yeah
terrible situation in Japan and they
have so many enemies now because of the
American presence China Russia the the
kural islands dispute is a different
story I've spoken about that a couple of
times at least the kural islands dispute
so that is what's happened to Japan so
they they are doing the best they
can and they are putting out enemy and
Jpop and whatever else and that's what
they are known for today that's what's
been done to them they have been
destroyed and their economy was was was
growing very rapidly in the in the 20th
century and it became the second largest
economy in the world and they could even
have have surpassed the us but the
Americans ruined them with the plaza
Accords then there was a slow decline
that's what happened but there has been
this nationalistic sentiment in Japan
you know there have been uh seeds of
nationalism so there is this author
called uh Yukio Mishima okay this guy
called yuk y Mishima he was a
nationalist a Japanese nationalist he
was a poet he was a writer one of the
most important writers in Japanese
language in the 20th century he was a
poet he was a writer he was a sports
person he was a model and he was a
Japanese nationalist let's let's put
this guy on the screen Yukio
Mishima so where is he where is
he okay here we have it
y
Mishima EX excellent I mean very
interesting writer this guy so he was a
Japanese nationalist as you can see very
martial guy
uh an author a
poet he was he he had these interesting
photographs and
poses and
he he tried to uh well he tried to bring
back the spirit of nationalism in Japan
he tried to make the Japanese people
understand that they were under
occupation they were being slowly
destroyed their country was slowly being
destroyed um and in 1970 I believe he
tried
to uh conduct a coup in Japan so he had
formed an organization a small
organization and they had been given
access to the Japanese self-defense
forces for some reason they were allowed
to train with them and in 1970 this guy
with three or four of his associates
went to the to one of the headquarters
of the Japanese self-defense forces and
and he took and he and he took control
of this thing and he he took this the
the commander of the of the headquarters
hostage and then he goes on the balcony
and gives this speech once again let's
put that on the screen where there must
be an image of the
speech there it is there is Yuko Mishima
giving a speech to the soldiers of the
Japanese self-defense forces in which is
trying to exhort them to to uh make
Japan free again free themselves from
American occupation have some
self-respect blah blah blah all that and
it was not successful the speech was not
successful the soldiers did not agree
with him and at the end of the speech he
went back inside he apologized to the
station commander and then he committed
seu which is also called harakiri which
is a ritual
suicide so there has been nationalistic
sentiments in Japan and I'm sure there
still is some of
that but yeah Japan is totally
controlled by the US and if you become a
little dangerous and a little powerful
you know what happens Shinzo OB is a
great example so there you have
it copile says you always say to refer
to history from multiple books and from
multiple sources but who actually knows
the truth of what happened in the past
the written things could be fabricated
and the stories that have been passed on
could be dubious if I'm the ruler I I
would not let anyone write bad things in
the texts maybe the rulers were doing
bad Deeds but they were showing their
people that they were good like
double-faced people I think most of the
history we know is a
lie look history I say read history from
multiple books multiple sources so the
source of history is not just
historiography and
writing there's archaeological evidence
there's much more to that so when it
comes to Roman times the the battles
they had with the Celtic peoples and
whatnot it's not just the Roman records
also archaeological evidence and which
kind of helps us reconstruct what
happened so it is not only about the
books that were written from that
period let me give you a pertinent
example you may have heard of these
people called the Vikings there was a
viking age from about the 700 600 700s
AD to about 1,000 something
ad the Viking age these were the people
who lived in Scandinavia the
Scandinavian people Pres day Sweden
Norway Denmark that region and you had
some of the some great rulers you had
the you had Rolo the Viking Rolo who is
the ancestor of every single king and
queen of England from one the year 1066
onwards you had Rolo you had semi
mythical figures like Ragnar lth Brook
you had uh you had canut the great you
had uh you had Harold
hardrada who invaded England in the year
1066 that was the end of the Viking age
because haral hard was
slain and so on now here's the deal the
Vikings what you are saying is that if
I'm the ruler I would not let anyone
write bad things in the
texts well if you read what the
Christians have written about the
Vikings you will see it's not anything
flattering or
complimentary so despite being these
great warriors and conquerors the
Vikings yeah only bad things have been
written about them because the Vikings
had the
swords and they did defeat the
Christians and all but eventually they
themselves became christianized and then
then the the monks in the Christian
church they all wrote terrible things
about the
Vikings look at the Mongols great rulers
great conquerors they have been
demonized to the to to Hell by Western
and Islamic
writers right even today there are all
these myths that are being spread about
the Mongols and their great ruler Shri
chingis Khan so it's not
entirely the way it looks okay history
is not always written by the winners by
the way when it comes to the Vikings and
the Mongols they were the winners but
who wrote the history the losers wrote
the history so it's not like that but I
agree with you much of history is a lie
that's what Napoleon said Napoleon
bonath history is a bunch of is a set of
Lies agreed upon so you have to discover
the truth of History
and there are people who are in love
with certain authors and certain in the
in in the standard narrative and you go
against that they say no no no you are
what whatever whatever they'll call you
names you know so that's how it is so
history a lot of history is lies I mean
look at Indian
history we don't India's historians
refuse to acknowledge the fact that
India has suffered the greatest genocide
in human history from the year let's say
1080 to the year 17 107 or so ad and
then a second genocide at the hands of
the British but you will not say that
see that written in any textbook so you
are right much of history is a lie and
we have to uncover the truth of
history but it's not always the winners
who write history sometimes it's the
losers who write history and we have two
examples here the Vikings and the
Mongols two questions Kepler's laws were
not div D based on Indian astronomical
data right taob bra's observations were
what helped Kepler right and the second
question is after the Europeans started
coming to India we saw a sudden surge in
the number number of scientific
discoveries taking place in the Western
World a lot of people have said that
these people have actually stolen our
knowledge and labeled them labeled this
knowledge as their own knowledge does
this hold any merits or are there any
other reasons for the same okay so these
two questions are actually related to
each other let's talk about Kepler's
laws three laws of planetary motion I'll
not tell you what the laws are that's a
different topic that's that belongs in a
physics live stream but Kepler's laws of
planetary motion and Kepler derived
these laws of planetary motion based on
the astronomical data that his teacher
his Guru taob had
compiled so
taob had this astronomical data and cap
Kepler
deduced his laws based on that
astronomical data so the question is it
was not based on the Indian astronomical
data right then Tao's observations were
the one that helped but the question is
where did Tao's observations come
from and I'm going to so the thing is
this my dear friends it is very
easy to tell lies but to debunk lies it
takes a 100 times the effort
because you to show 78 pieces of
evidence and put it all together it is
so easy to put out misinformation it is
so easy to lie and the Europeans have
been lying about this for centuries and
the true sources of the knowledge are
lost so let me show you
some some evidence based not on my
research but based on the research done
by others okay this is not my research
so so let me put some stuff on the
screen okay let's let's take a look at
this remove this so what does it say
this is a research paper from jst it
says it's by
asan it says the earliest extent extent
Arabic arithmetic the earliest extent
Arabic arithmetic what is it called
okay and they call it a blatant it's a
in just imagine the blatancy of this lie
the book's name
isab Al Hindi but they are saying it's
the earliest extent Arabic arithmetic
how barefaced of a lie can this can can
you have this is that
okay so let me give you a different
thing
here uh this is an a book that's
available online the arithmetic of
Al the story of Hindu Arabic arithmetic
As Told in
the so over here they're calling it
Hindu Arabic arithmetic so at least
they're not lying completely and the
arithmetic was of whom it was of Al
and this is the real uid there was no
uid ukl is a myth the real euklid was
this guy Al was a translator who
translated Indian arithmetic and
mathematical texts into Arabic now I'm
going to show you some tweets by a
gentleman called Joseph noi he has done
a tremendous amount of research so all
this research is entirely his none of it
is mine all the credit goes to him so
here's the first
tweet so wh donu Cambridge PhD proved
that Kepler did not make the original
data needed for his laws he had poor
vision from smallpox Kepler Johannes
Kepler his master Tao's Mars orbit is
also suspect where did the data come
from which other astronomer had
elliptical Mars data is the question and
who and and and there's evidence that
this is all
fabricated one second
let's put that on the screen and this is
the research paper that he is talking
about if it does turn up on the screen
here it is okay Kepler's fabricated
figures covering up the mess in the new
astronomy this was published in
1988 okay he had
fabricated these
figures so how did this happen and where
did Kepler where did taob get all this
data and all that so taob was a close
associate of Jesuit Scholars who were
the Jesuits the Jesuits were the
scientific thieves associated with the
Vatican church so they were scholars in
their own right and their job was to go
to various Nations like India
Mesopotamia China wherever and steal
Knowledge from there and they were well
versed in science the Jesuits so Kepler
was a close ass associate of Jesuit
Scholars and the Jesuits even stole
philosophical text and all that so much
Indian philosophy has been digested into
the west and presented his Western
philosophy but we talking about Kepler
here so and taob so taob brah was a
close associate of Jesuit Scholars he
published the same planetary model of
nilakanta who lived before him but Tao
used simple circular orbits instead of
mathematically complex eccentric orbits
of nilakanta and Kepler inherited all of
Tao's documents do you understand what
happened okay that is what happened now
let's see something
else so all of this research is is
entirely by Joseph n not by me I'm just
putting it out here if you think it's
possible for two people to come up with
the same complex astronomical models
independently read this passage by uto
noer regarded as the foremost historian
of Science of course he didn't apply the
standard on Newton madava or Kepler
nanta so you can read this you can you
can pause the screen and read this if
you like but I'm going to move on to the
next
Tweet now here is more evidence
there's plenty of evidence of Jesuit
manuscript Gathering activities in
Kerala including a direct statement by
Mato Richi and even a request by Kepler
to a Jesuit for more Eclipse data from
India 16th 17th century Europe was doing
Mass plagiarism of Indian texts and
there is a sample of this over
here
okay next next tweet
so the implications cannot be allowed to
go unrecognized Europe was digesting the
manuscripts of the Indian Trio arabat
brahmagupta and bascara for close to 500
years before Galileo threw things down
the Tower of Pisa and apples fall fell
on Newton
okay
next
next just like taob stole the erroneous
planetary model of nilakanta Galileo
chose to use the exact same analogy used
by Arya bataa to describe relativity a
thousand years after Arya Bata the boat
the verses 9 and 10 of ARA's astronomy
section describe it and Galileo used
exactly the same thing okay and here is
a research paper by Professor by Dr CK
Raju calculus
transmission how are the aryaa the 24
sign values and much more where
transmitted essentially they were stolen
by
Europe so you can check this out you can
Google this calculus transmission by CK
Raju in case you don't know how to use
Google Google it and check it out so so
there is plenty of evidence but it is
not easy to find you have to do some
hard work and dig all this
up all these false claims they're easily
accessible on Wikipedia in various
textbooks in various history books all
these false claims are are R okay that
all that everything was independently
discovered by Europeans but when you but
to but to make the connections between
the Jesuits and taob and the Jesuits in
Kepler and the Jesuits in Kerala and the
aryati and all that information is
hidden deep beneath the surface it's
very hard to discover this and that's
why all credited to Joseph noi and for
Dr Dr s Raju etc for doing this
tremendous work and the other authors
who who have also been doing this so
that is the deal the Europeans have been
Mass plagiarizing Indian history and
today everything is attributed to Europe
all this science all the mathematics all
the philosophy which they have stolen
from
India but yeah we need to bring this out
in the public and I'm glad many authors
are actually doing the taking the time
to do the Deep research needed to expose
these
Brads okay theas Theus says how does
zebu cattle counter AIT Arian Invasion
theory is is there an migration tourism
picnic theory is there any evidence of
the out of India migration of them the
cattle would could have existed in
multiple areas at the same time okay
what is they just refering to let's put
that on the screen uh I'll put one one
uh example of this on the screen we're
talking about the cattle so this is a
report from 2019 in f.org it's a physics
website but I found it here because I
read physics things so it says ancient
genomics pinpoint
origin and Rapid turnover of cattle in
the Fertile Crescent which means the
West Asia region middle east region okay
so and this is an example of aibu shaped
weight from T Beth
shesh U the keeping of livestock began
blah blah blah blah blah ancient DNA has
revealed how the prehistory of the
world's largest domestic animal the cow
chimes with these
events uh sequencing boine ancient boine
genomes and so on so a dramatic change
happened about 4,000 years ago when we
detect a widespread wholesale influx of
zebu genetics from the East okay zebu
genetics which means
bossus uh no sorry boss indicas zebu
cattle zebu cattle are boss indicas and
they originate in India in the Indian
subcontinent and from the perspective of
these westerners the Indus Valley region
so suddenly around 4,000 years ago there
was a massive widespread influx of zebu
C
into the Middle East from India okay and
this was the
beginning uh and and you find this in
the Middle East in West Asia you also
find this in Mesopotamia which is West
Asia and you also find this in
Egypt and so on and today you will find
that most cattle in this region and most
cattle across Africa have Indian cattle
genetics that's what you find and just
for your reference if you are wondering
what zebu cattle are I think we are all
familiar with them in India but let's
just show an image of zeu
cattle zeu that's
it zebu cattle so this is your standard
Indian bull right the Indus Valley you
you see these bulls and cows in the IND
Indus Valley stamps in the Saraswati
Hindu so-called harapan
uh those seals and all that right
so this is the Indus Valley uh
cow and that's the that's the zebu
cattle that we are referring to okay
let's take that off the screen
so so it doesn't counter the Arian
Invasion migration tourism picnic
spacecraft myth at all it actually does
something
else understand this cattle are domestic
animals right so a bunch of cattle will
not wake up tomorrow morning and say hey
let's let's uh let's go to the Middle
East and then they all pack their bags
and 10 10,000
cattle go off on a March for several
thousand kilometers from India and reach
the Middle East cattle don't behave like
that cattle do things their masters tell
them and they go wherever their masters
go so if a bunch of cattle large scale
massive influx of zebu cattle happens in
the Middle East and and that part of
Africa Egypt at
about 4,000 years ago it means these
cattle came with Indians who went there
the cattle don't travel on their own so
what does that tell you this alleged
Arian Invasion migration picnic whatever
whatever happened happened allegedly
around 1500 ad right that's what the
theory says so that's 3,500 years before
today but we are talking about the
migration of Indians in large numbers
westwards 4,000 years
ago so this is the out of India Theory
we're talking about we're not trying
this this the presence of the evidence
of zebu cattle in this region doesn't
counter the O the AIT it bolsters the
oit that Indians were traveling
westwards for thousands of years before
today there's so much evidence of that
but these people want to minimize that
and they want to disregard that okay so
this is the evidence of out of India
migration there are so many other pieces
of evidence of out of India migration we
have the
uh we have the
bodh Sutra which is a late Vic text that
talks about the migration westwards of
amasu and he goes in the region of
Gandhara and Arata and paru Gandhara we
know it's Afghanistan present
Afghanistan paru means Persia but Arata
could be Armenia Mount Ararat so there
is that but there is literary evidence
then we have
uh who are these guys Hittites
hurrians washuk was the capital of whom
let me just quickly Google that
vukani vukani was mitani miani the miani
Empire that existed about 1500 BC in
Anatolia in Anatolia in present day
Syria they spoke what language they
spoke Sanskrit late Vic
Sanskrit late Vic
Sanskrit okay and we have the oldest
evidence of written Sanskrit in Syria
present day Syria
uh yeah so that's another evidence of
outof India migration and then there's
much more I will not go into the detail
so there is so much so much tremendous
amounts of evidence of out of India
migrations way before the so-called
alleged Arian Invasion migration thing
happened so the evidence of zebu cattle
it actually bolsters the out of India
story of course the migrations out of
India and you find the the first
evidence the the earliest evidence that
we have of of Indian cattle in Egypt
also around 4,000 years before today so
and the cattle did not exist in multiple
areas at the same time we know when the
first influx of cattle happened it's
around 4,000 years before today that's
when the first influx of Indian cattle
in this region happened it is known
scientific data there is no evidence of
Indian cattle genetics in this region
before that or Indian cattle bones or
anything so that is evidence of an outof
India
migration right
next
question s borya says was the telescope
invented by Indians as some ancient
texts mention something like a telescope
okay uh I have seen no evidence of any
okay if there are texts that mention it
you can you can refer I mean you can
specify what text they are that would
help me to to investigate this but as
far as I know I have not seen any
evidence of ancient texts mentioning a
telescope Indian text I mean so as far
as I know Indians ancient Indians did
not invent the telescope that's strange
actually because Indians ancient Indians
invented in in so so many things but the
telescope apparently wasn't among those
things that they invented so
yeah
next samud Cas say there are
security there are security issues in
the T20 World Cup and threats given by
ISIS apparently what's your take on this
there is a Champions Trophy in Pakistan
next year what decision do you think the
government would take on sending the
Indian team to Pakistan okay when it
comes to the T20 World Cup I believe
it's it's starting tomorrow if I'm not
mistaken and it's being held in the
Caribbean which is the West Indies and
in the United States and apparently Isis
or whatever some some terrorist
organization organizations have given
some threats so I would say uh it is the
duty and responsibility of the host
Nations to ensure the complete Safety
and Security of the teams so I think we
have to trust the Americans the United
States and the Caribbean Nations to to
make sure that there is proper security
of the Indian players and if required
the Indian government and the or the
BCCI can send extra security uh so yeah
I I'm sure they will do whatever is
necessary but yeah India is a target
India is a nation that's growing the
economy is growing India is becoming
more relevant geopolitically and in a
variety of other ways and it's it's
something that lots of people don't like
especially in the west and when it comes
to Isis I would recommend you read the
book black flags that will tell you who
actually created
Isis all right now about the Champions
Trophy in Pakistan next year obviously
we should not send our players there how
can you send an Indian team to Pakistan
a temporary Nation an artificial and
temporary nation and obviously the
epicenter of global terrorism you can't
do that so what India should do what the
BCCI should do is arm twist the IC into
holding the Champions Trophy elsewhere
not in
Pakistan and arm twist the other nations
also to say that we will not go to
Pakistan arm twist the BCC has has
enough money now to arm twist everybody
it wants so use the money use the
leverage arm twist everybody arm twist
the ICC arm twist Australia South Africa
England whoever else and ensure that if
the Champions Trophy is held in Pakistan
nobody goes
there okay Afghanistan you tell not to
go Afghanistan's home base is anywh
India anyhow so that's what needs to
happen next question is by gorov I've
heard someone said that today Sri Lanka
is not the Lanka where Lord Ram went and
yeah uh it's somewhere in Malaysia or
Indonesia is that true and is there any
evidence for this and where to start
learning the truth okay let's talk about
this thing that's two questions in here
look I'm not sure who has made these
claims and if it's one person multiple
people okay I'm not going to get into
that but uh look okay maybe maybe Lord
Ram went to bwana maybe he went to New
Zealand I mean there's this place called
Lanka Sri Lanka but we have to disregard
that right he maybe maybe he went to
Botswana maybe he went to New Zealand
maybe maybe he went to Czechoslovakia
Lord RAM and maybe rahan was was
slak yeah I
mean look as far as I I understand
things I'm sure I'm not a very
intelligent person very little knowledge
so maybe I'm wrong but as far as I know
as so as far as I see things Lanka and
Sri Lanka the same
thing okay and and if if so if it was
let's say Botswana or if it was
Czechoslovakia or if it was New Zealand
or if it was Malaysia or Indonesia
where's the where's the bridge the
bridge that was built we have have a
bridge between India and Sri Lanka right
is there where's the bridge so I don't
know what sense it makes uh so I don't
take this the theory seriously I'm sure
people have done a lot of research and
hard work and all but come on that
doesn't mean Theory should be every
Theory should be taken seriously so I
don't agree with this of course I may be
wrong obviously there are people more
intelligent than me out there but that's
my perspective if it is not Sri Lanka it
could be Botswana or Czechoslovakia or
New Zealand or or maybe Mexico
go Arijit B says how to get addicted to
studies I've lost all interest in my
studies how do you convince yourself to
study when you were in school I am in
the 10th standard please give some
advice for
boards I've been
there you know the problem you face as a
student is you don't understand what is
the point of what you're
doing as a child as a young person you
want to go and have some fun you want to
go and play or you want to have meet
with your friends and you want some time
for yourself and for having some fun but
you made to study study study and you
don't see the point of studying what am
I going to get by studying all this by
memorizing all this crap all this
garbage what's the point and that's why
people get get frustrated people get
depressed people get disillusioned
people lose interests and then they
perform poorly in their in their exams
and then the consequences become
apparent so
you have to see it this way you will
have no motivation or interest in your
studies unless you have a long-term
goal so you're in the 10th standard
right do you have a goal a vision for
yourself of where you want to be when
you are 30 years old what do you want to
have achieved by the time you're 30
years old what you need to do is you
need to paint a great grand picture of a
future of a great
future think of the greatest thing you
could do with whatever potential you
have and imagine that you want to do
that by the age of
30 and then you want to work backwards
from there okay let's say I want to be
the next Elon Musk let's say
hypothetically okay let's say you want
to be the Indian Elon Musk you want to
have a valuation of your company of $500
billion dollars by the age of 30 let's
say let's say there's no harm in
thinking big so you want to do that by
the age of
30 so then you work backwards then by
the age of 25 what do you would you need
to have achieved if you want to do that
by the age of 30 then by the age of 22
what do you need to achieve then by the
age of 20 what do you have to achieve
then does it mean that you need to have
a good good College college education
and does it mean that you need to do to
get into a good college you need to get
good marks in the 12th and 10th exams
when you see that way the cause and
effect change then suddenly you get the
motivation oh my God I want to do that
so let me get these good marks now and
let's study doesn't matter if it's good
if if the syllabus is good or not I I am
doing this for a purpose and then
everything becomes worthwhile so my
point is I'm just giving a very random
hypothetical example maybe a very
hyperbolic example the point is you need
to know where you want to go and then
you need to find the right pathway by
working backwards in time and you don't
have to reinvent the wh think of the
greatest people you admire and how they
achieved their thing and how did they
reach where they've reached that will
show you the path and usually for most
people you don't want to be Elon Musk
right for most people let's say you want
to have a good job with a with a package
of 50 lakhs a year let's say so for that
you will need to have a good degree
college degree University degree which
means you will need to get into a great
College which means you need a good you
know good performance in the 12th and
10th standard exam so when that big
thing at at the age of 30 motivates you
when you can see it and then you will
see what path you have to go through
then it Mak sense then you will get the
interest back in
studies but if you have no great dreams
or something
no great objective no great ambition
then it is very hard to be motivated my
point is be
ambitious think of what you want to
achieve in life think big be ambitious
be have big dreams and then F work
backwards and then see if if if your
path has to go through getting good
marks and if if it is the case then you
will be motivated
right okay what next do we
have let me
see okay shashwat says do you love
watching Martin's
coresi movies I like I like movies I'm a
movie buff you give me the chance I'll
watch two movies a week on on the big
screen in a movie theater but today
there's no good movies around terrible
so yeah one of the great uh directors is
Martin scorsi I've seen many of his
movies U couple of movies with Robert
Deniro taxi driver was one Raging Bull
the black and white movie where he's a
boxer that's a good one good Fellas then
cassino is a good movie Gangs of New
York uh with one of the great actors
what's his name the guy who his first
movie was Gandhi Richard atur Gandhi
okay the guy who was in Gangs of New
York then you have the Aviator with
what's his name Leonardo de Caprio then
there is The Departed then there is a
movie called Hugo children's movie so
I've seen a bunch of his movies and I'm
a big movie buff overall and Martin
scorsi is one of the greatest for
sure all right that is it for the
questions that I have selected now let's
take some questions from the live chat
ah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah our friend
Dixie
Dixie has pointed out the name Daniel
deis you've been watching Austin Powers
have we
okay okay what other questions do okay
let's let's do some live chat questions
all
right okay crew wit says if white Arians
who migrated to the east founded Indian
civilization why did Arians who migrated
to the West could not create a superior
civilization and the Germans remain
primitive for many Millennia oh my God
you have destroyed all the arguments in
one
shot yeah the white Superior Arians who
migrated to the East and to India and
Persia they founded the Indian
civilization and Persian civilization
right but another branch of these Arians
allegedly also went into Europe so why
did those Arians not create any great
civilization why were they eating raw
meat until 2,000 years ago and why were
they living in trees and caves do you
know how the Germans behaved the
Germanic tribes the whatever the names
were chuski and whatever those Germanic
tribes the Romans have described the the
behavior of the Germanic peoples they
used to be clothed in animal skins half
naked and they would live like wild
beasts live alone in the forests to
prove how strong they were and then they
would have this Tribal wars and all that
so yeah extremely good point of course
they will said the the Greeks the Greeks
founded a civilization well the Greeks
are hardly white by
way you take two people side by side
okay you take to make
take a Nordic person and take a Greek
person have them stand side by side the
Greek guy will look like me he'll not
look
white okay the Mediterranean peop the
Greek people and the Italians they're
not really white from the Nordic
perspective but according to these
eurocentric supremacist people the true
Arians are the nordics right Nordic
people the blond haired blue-eyed pale
skinned people the Greeks and Italians
are not like
that so you you can't say that the
Greeks were the Arians your Arians your
so-called Arians are are the Nordic
people so where was that Superior Nordic
civilization have you seen the Vikings
they used to they still eat raw fish
pickled herrings and what is
that shark they eat the the root in
shark they eat they take shark they chop
it into gigantic pieces they bury it
underground for 6
months then they take it out and then
they eat something like that there's
some process that behind that but it
is uh I don't know if it's even an
acquired taste I don't remember what
they call that the rotten shark thing
but I think it's banned in many
civilized
countries that they have some good good
food of course they have
uh what soup what soup is that I forget
qu sua or something like that they have
some it's it's turnips and carrots and
potatoes and meat or maybe fish that
sort of thing the point is there was no
great Nordic civilization there was no
great Germanic
civilization even 2,000 years ago you
didn't have that even a thousand years
ago you were you had the beginning of
the Germanic thing uh carolus Magnus
Char man the king of the Franks he had
conquered Germanic territories through
the northern Crusades and all so you
make a great Point here sir you made a
great you make a great point there was
no European civilization they remained
Prim Primitives primitive for so
long okay next the
question
uh false stol says will we see a World
War I before 2100 I hope not I hope not
but maybe we will maybe we will I think
one of the things we could see soon is
the India China war it could happen Okay
and India is going to have to be very
very very careful and India will have to
build its military might its military
capabilities very
rapidly Vin Kosik says the rotten shark
dish is called hakar outstanding thank
you so much for that
H okay durti says what can a 12th pass
guy 30 years old with no other degrees
do to make a living or earn good money
please suggest I'm all years and ready
to commit look I whatever advice I may
give it cannot be taken as Financial
advice or career advice okay I'm
just I'm not putting my money on the
line okay I have nothing to lose so I I
can give you some
suggestions or some
opinions but you have to be very careful
about that if you're 12th pass you don't
have a college degree University degree
okay cool it means that you will not get
a job one of the corporations all who
want all these degrees they are slaves
to degrees show me this degree show me
that degree why don't you have first
class why do you have why don't you have
distinction why don't you have a degree
from this college or that great College
why from that college why not from the
iits why not from this IIT all that
nonsense they care about degrees they
don't care about your abilities so if
you don't if you are only 12th pass you
will not get a job in any of these
corporations and all that so what can
you do I think the best thing you can do
is be an entrepreneur be a business
person obviously you will need to invest
some money for that and you know these
days we have good schemes government
schemes you get loans for doing that so
you have to find a sector an area that
is underserved you to find a segment of
the population that is not that is being
ignored and you have to solve their
problems that is essentially what a
business idea is there is an existing
Gap there's an existing problem in
society Society needs Solutions but
nobody has provided the solution so you
go and provide the solution or maybe
there are solutions but they are not
good enough so you provide a better
solution so that's what you can do so
that that is what business is
essentially and uh if you give value to
society Society will give you value back
in the form of money that's how it works
that is a very broad General thing I'm
telling you so if you just have a 12th
standard degree no issue I don't I don't
see think that you are lower than others
I don't care about degrees personally so
I think you you you're going to have to
uh if you want to make good good money
then then you're going to have to go
into business entrepreneurship but it is
very dangerous very difficult not easy
and it's your money that you're putting
on the line so it's not for everyone and
you have to be very careful but you also
have to take risks so that is the thing
about being an
entrepreneur so yeah that's what I can
tell you I am no expert in these matters
you should ask uh uh real business
experts but I would say that would be
the right path for you because you want
to earn good money you want to be rich
that's a great thought to have that's a
great ambition to have I can promise you
you will never become rich working for
somebody else you will never become rich
working a 9 to5 job or whatever job okay
it jobs are not 9 to5 they're 9 to2 me 9
in the morning to 12: in the night
that's how it jobs are I know I've been
a cyber once so even that won't
make you rich you will never become rich
working on a salary earning a salary so
if you want to be rich you have to start
your own business you to become an
entrepreneur which obviously is not an
easy task but that is the way to
go okay next vinit says as a vegetarian
I'm stunned I'm I'm expecting you
talking about the raw shark the the the
rotten shock the fermented
shock uh Miguel says P or makach who
wins I want them for to win I hope so I
hope he wins
uh bishal mahapatra says is Nikita Krush
the best Soviet leader have you seen
that video or that photo of him at the
United Nations security Council he took
his shoe in his hand and he was
hammering the the podium with with a
shoe very dramatic let's let's try and
Google that shall we let's Google it why
not let us Google
nikf let us do
that ch Sho yeah here you have it shoe
shoe banging
incident there you have it at the United
Nations he takes a shoe in his hand and
he slams it on the
[Laughter]
podium Nikita
kushev so yeah that's kind of what he's
remembered for not for the other work do
I think he is the best Soviet leader no
I don't think
so it's Nikita Kush who starts the
decline of the USSR with the lowering of
Standards you know when it comes to the
most
efficacious overall best
leader most people won't like what I say
but it's Joseph
Stalin yeah I think Joseph Stalin was
the best Soviet leader despite
everything he did okay which was
definitely terrible absolutely
terrible okay let's take a few more
questions uh I can see lots and lots and
lots of
questions um
apurva says similar to your advice I was
a very ambitious student but I ended up
in a private college along with mental
health issues my interest in Studies
have also diminished and any
advice my advice is very simple your
studies are just a small phase of your
life of course of course you've been
studying since you were three years old
or whatever age and you have to do it
for the first 20 years of your life okay
I get it it's terrible but the real life
that going to live is what comes after
your
studies and that's what you have to plan
for so let's say you you are in a
private college and you're not happy
that you are not in one of the top
universities or whatever it is that is
not the point whether you get a degree
from the top IIT or the top university
or a random college at the end of the
day what really matters is what you do
with your life you will have people who
were Toppers in their class and by the
age of 35 they in some poor not poor in
in a very unremarkable job doing a very
good job of of being a good employee but
you may have somebody who was never a
Topper who owns the company that happens
my point is you need to First understand
who you are what are your strengths and
weaknesses what are your aptitudes what
are you actually born to do and then you
to pursue that and it doesn't matter
what what the education system does to
you so you get your degree or whatever
you get out of it you fix your mental
health by lifting weights out would or
whichever way whichever way works for
you but you have to succeed in life
which means you to make a career for
yourself in something either
in in in whatever I mean whatever you
whatever it is that you that is best for
you whether it is business
entrepreneurship whether it is in in the
academic system whether it is as an
employee somewhere manager you have to
find what is right for you which means
you to spend some time alone and
introspect and understand yourself most
people don't even know who they
are most people are scared to be
alone I have known people like
that okay I've known people who said
that oh if I were alone I would go crazy
why would you go crazy man but that's
how it is most people so you have to
develop some mental strength mental
fortitude and figure out who you are are
and what you want to do in life and then
to hell with the education system hell
with whatever happened you get out of
that and you move on in with life easier
said than done but you got to find a way
you've got to find a way and you got to
work really hard for that that's how it
goes nothing is easy no good thing is
easy nothing valuable is ever easy in
life so that's what I will say do well
all the best sir
Aura Warrior says do you think a person
like Shri Krishna will ever be
born why can okay yeah maybe in the
future it's possible it happened in the
past it may happen
again sham badw says Pakistan has
admitted in their high court that P
Pakistan occupied Kashmir is foreign
territory from their perspective what
are My Views My Views are it doesn't
make any
difference they are in possession of Po
that is called having facts on the
ground take technically it may be a
foreign territory technically it may be
this or that but their armed forces are
there and currently they are in
possession of this territory so those
are the facts on the ground and these
Court things don't make any difference
I'm a realistic person I don't care
about words and documents and all that
the facts on the ground are the facts on
the ground okay that's how I see it but
it's a temporary situation we know that
Pakistan is a temporary artificial
nation and
and I hope the people of Pakistan get
some freedom from this horrible
atrocious Army that is running the
country
uh geopolitical duas says I don't like
any sport is it a bad thing why is it
necessarily a bad thing it's up to you
maybe you like other stuff maybe that's
see you should not be concerned about
other people's opinions about personal
things
so if you don't like a sport or or or
some people may not like I don't know
music some people may not like movies
it's your choice why is it good or bad
it is who you are Embrace who you are
okay it's fine I have no issue with you
not liking any sport entirely entirely
perfectly fine no
issues any defense book suggestions for
NDA aspirants I don't know anything
about n da what goes into the
preparation so I am not the right person
to ask this question I have no idea
whatsoever the suggestions I may give
you maybe completely inappropriate for
that particular kind of exam preparation
or whatever preparation so I am sorry I
apologize but I don't have the answer to
this
question
okay
um okay what else do we have what else
do we
have um
aush Mishra says it's the UCL final
which team are you supporting what is
UCL let let me let
me let's Google it
together not
this uh give me a second I I have to go
to Google right what is UCL I'm sure I
know what it is but I'm right now my
mind is blank
UCL oh UFA Champions League of course of
course today's the final is it when is
the final who's playing dormund and the
Real Madrid tomorrow or tonight 12:30
a.m. which team am I supporting I shall
support Real
Madrid because they are real they are
royal I don't know much about B dund of
course I know the name and I've heard of
it since I was a kid but let's say I
support the Real Madrid because they
good all right uh let's take some more
questions uh Malik Sayad says tips for
IIT ex J exam drop your strategy what's
a drop year you take one year off and
then you do the exam is it is it is it
that so uh um when it comes to exam
preparation you to understand that the
objective is not to acquire knowledge
it's just to pass the exam okay so you
have to be practical and realistic it's
like a military campaign when you are
when you are on a military campaign you
and you have an objective you want to
capture this territory you don't go and
capture everything around that your
objective you have one job and one job
only go and capture the territory
similarly when it comes to passing an
exam clearing an exam and doing well in
it you only want to clear the exam with
the best possible marks to hell with the
knowledge the knowledge you can acquire
later during your IIT two three years
whatever four years so my point is it
has to be exam focused get as many exam
papers of the last 70 80 years you have
and every day solve one paper do it over
and over again in exam like situation
conditions that's what I would say
Obviously you to First acquire the
knowledge that you need to solve the
exam paper so but you should spend the
last three months just solving every day
one exam paper just do it over and over
again you'll become good at it that's
what I would say from what I have
experienced long
ago mclen say does is it worth becoming
a commercial pilot look if you enjoy
flying if you find it fascinating being
up in the clouds and having the control
of the aircraft uh it's fun I'm sure in
that case it's fun you get to see stuff
that very few people get to see and uh
I'm sure the pay is good and you get to
travel all over the place all over the
world if you're a domestic pilot you can
still travel all over the country if
you're an international pilot you can
travel all over the world stay in five
star
hotels if if you if you that and
whatever else right so if you if if
that's the life for you travel and
living in fancy
hotels and uh flying aircraft if if it's
and and good money I'm sure then yeah
maybe it's worth worth doing that but
I'm sure it's not easy I'm sure that's
lot that lots of people want to get into
this job and it's not I'm sure there's a
huge demand for this so you have to be
realistic all right let's take a couple
more questions and then we are
done MyUI says what's the atmology of
the world will the Beast I think it is
Dutch or
Africans Africans is a language that is
closely related to
Dutch so I think will the Beast is
either Dutch or
Africans and it's it's an animal it's an
African animal right it's it's one of
those gazelle like gigantic robust
gazelle t an like
animals
yeah endan says is North Korea fully
sovereign country or vasal state of
China or Russia look it desires to be a
fully sovereign country but it's not and
it's a wasal of not Russia but China it
has some Russian connection also because
Russia is not really far uh but yeah
mostly wasal of China and they don't
want to be that if I recall correctly
the current leader Mr Kim Jong-un his
father had told him that China is is the
nation with which we must have the best
relations but China is the nation that
wants to interfere the most in our
country so you have to play that game
the tightrope walk and you have to unify
the Korean Peninsula with South Korea so
there that's what uh Kim jong-un's
father Kim ilung Son said to him
allegedly
um Primal Raj says can India develop
high yield hydrogen weapons or low yield
fishing weapons both both but for that
you test and I'm sure you can't test
today so you have to do simulations you
to do subcritical tests and things like
that of course India can develop high
yield hydrogen weapons hydrogen weapon
means a thermonuclear nuclear
thermonuclear Weapon It's a fishion
fusion device in which the fusion
reaction is triggered by the initial
fishion reaction that's what it is and
of course low yield fishing weapons
anybody can build I mean not anybody but
you need to have the ingredients the
spice mix you need to have and you need
to need to have some technical know how
so engineering work uh yeah so India can
do
both Rohit says Lenin versus Stalin who
was the greatest I would say
Stalin was greater I am not condoning
the things that Stalin has done okay by
any means but I'm saying overall Lenin
versus Stalin I would say Stalin was
greater all
right H zi says is India's drone
industry now getting world class
idea Forge in andani defense look I
think it is India is going to be one of
the major drone manufacturers and the
more you manufacture the better you get
the more you can iterate and more
variations of drones you can come up
with so I think in a decade in there is
going to be the world's largest drone
manufacturing country most likely so
yeah it's it's great going I'm very
happy to see
this Krishna SAR says your opinion on
green hydrogen as a source of
sustainable energy fuel Etc is mainly
mainly in trans what is green hydrogen I
think somebody had spoken to me about
this was it a minister on one of my
podcasts it's possible uh let me just
quickly Google what is green hydrogen I
forgot uh green hydrogen green
hydrogen okay water electrolysis of
course of course so what you do is very
simple you take water and you put an
anode and a cathode in there and you
break break water into pieces
essentially so you you you
so what you do is you take the hydrogens
away from the oxygen that's what you do
okay and as a result you get hydrogen
and oxygen and you get rid of the oxygen
and you have green hydrogen left so that
hydrogen is acquired by by electrolyzing
water I think it's a reasonably good
source of sustainable energy because in
fuel transportation because it is the
the source is essentially Limitless
ocean ocean water it's Limitless
source so until until we start doing too
much perhaps but I think yeah for now I
think it's a good good source of
sustainable energy or fuel for
transportation Etc I think it's it's a
it's a good bet and uh there's
no
bad byproduct of that of this technology
so yeah it's
good uh I saw a good question it
disappeared let's see
okay let's take this one himank says and
this is the last question for today okay
we're going to end with this uh will
Saudi Arabia go nuclear if Iran acquires
nuclear weapons I think they'll try to
do that because that's a big threat for
them it's a big danger for them they'll
be from their perspective from the Saudi
perspective Iran is a big threat because
Saudi Arabia first of all is a US
Ally and it's a sunnia thing and Iran is
an ancient empire in India is an Iran is
an ancient civilization and there's been
historical hostility for a variety of
reasons between the Arabs and the
Persians so yeah and uh from the balance
of power perspective I think Iran and
Saudi Arabia have roughly similar hard
power score so yes if Iran acquires
nuclear weapons Saudi Arabia will try
their best to themselves acquire nuclear
weapons and they will try for sure how
will they acquire nuclear weapons I'm
not sure the Americans for sure won't
give them maybe they'll try and buy
nukes from Pakistan when it comes to
Pakistan everything is a price so maybe
the Saudis will try and buy nukes from
Pakistan they will not approach India
for that because India will not give
them nuclear weapons India is not a
proliferator of nuclear technology so I
think the best bet for Saudi Arabia is
to go and approach Pakistan and try to
pay them for a bunch of nukes maybe 20
30 nukes how much would it cost we have
uh money how much how much what's your
price essentially all right with that
I'm going to end this session thank you
once again everybody for participating
asking so many wonderful
questions uh and I will see you as as
usual in the next live stream next week
today is Saturday so I'll see you on
Wednesday most likely in the next live
stream which is going to be completely
uh live chat live stream all right so
thank you so much once again and I will
see you soon take care and keep raising
your standards bye